Karly Jacobsen

Address 868 Neil Avenue, Columbus, OH 43215 • Phone (904) 534-6363 • Email karlyj@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Expertise in mathematical model formulation, analysis and interpretation for biological systems. Solid fundamentals in numerical computation, optimization, and data manipulation. Proven skills in leadership, multidisciplinary collaboration, and communication. Self-directed learner with high attention to detail.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. Mathematics UNIVERSITY OF FLORIDA Gainesville, FL	May 2013 GPA 4.00
M.S. Mathematics UNIVERSITY OF FLORIDA Gainesville, FL	May 2010 GPA 4.00
B.S. Materials Science & Engineering UNIVERSITY OF FLORIDA Gainesville, FL	May 2007 GPA 4.00

EXPERIENCE

Ohio State University: Mathematical Biosciences Institute

2013 – present

Postdoctoral fellow

Columbus, OH

- Collaborated on five interdisciplinary modeling projects with mathematicians, statisticians, and clinicians
- Developed a partial differential equations model for the immune response to tumor virotherapy and performed *in silico* experiments to predict efficacy of potential combination therapies
- Formulated epidemic models and pioneered a metric to improve prediction of disease outbreaks on networks
- Performed parameter estimation for various models using preclinical and epidemiological time-series data
- Effectively communicated results in four research publications and over 20 presentations to diverse audiences

University of Florida: Department of Mathematics

2008 - 2013

Fellow, research assistant, teaching assistant, course coordinator

Gainesville, FL

- Constructed the first predictive model for an innovative tumor therapy and developed simulation algorithm
- Built and analyzed an ODE model to provide insight on the agricultural management of a citrus disease
- Effectively taught 19 undergraduate mathematics course sections with class sizes from 16 to over 200
- Managed team of course instructors, spearheaded curriculum redesign and authored a royalty-generating textbook supplement for the AIM Mathematics Program

University of Florida: Biomaterials Center

2005 - 2007

Undergraduate research assistant

Gainesville, FL

- Synthesized and characterized DNA microspheres for optimal drug uptake during intratumoral chemotherapy
- Performed statistical analysis of microsphere particle size data using SigmaStat software

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Johnson & Johnson Vision Care

June – August 2006

Intern, Process and product development engineer

Jacksonville, FL

- Developed test method and collected hydrogel swelling data for contact lens processing
- Analyzed data, presented results and actively participated in project team meetings with process engineers

SKILLS & COURSES

R	Matlab	Numerical optimization	Probability theory	Applied differential equations
Git	LaTeX	Parameter estimation	Stochastic models	Statistical learning

PUBLICATIONS

- **K. Jacobsen**, M. Burch, J. Tien and G. Rempala. *The large graph limit of a stochastic epidemic model on a dynamic multilayer network*. Submitted to J. Math. Biol.
- M. Burch, **K. Jacobsen**, J. Tien and G. Rempala. *Network-based analysis of a small Ebola outbreak*. Math. Biosci. (in press).
- **K. Jacobsen**, L. Russell, B. Kaur and A. Friedman. 2015. *Effects of CCN1 and macrophage content on glioma virotherapy: A mathematical model*. Bull. Math. Biol. (77): 984-1012.
- **K. Jacobsen** and S. S. Pilyugin. 2015. *Analysis of a mathematical model for tumor therapy with a fusogenic oncolytic virus*. Math. Biosci. (270): 169-182.
- **K. Jacobsen**, J. Stupiansky, and S. S. Pilyugin. 2013. *Mathematical modeling of citrus groves infected by huanglongbing*. Math. Biosci. Eng. 10 (3): 705-728.

SELECT PRESENTATIONS

- A modeling framework for an epidemic with multiple modes of transmission on a dynamic network. University of Pittsburgh, Applied Mathematics Seminar, Pittsburgh, PA. March 2016.
- *Residence time and epidemics on networks.* University of Florida, Biomathematics Seminar, Gainesville, FL. March 2015.
- Modeling disease spread on networks with a new notion of distance. Ohio Wesleyan University Science Lecture Series, Delaware, OH. January 2015.
- Modeling the effects of macrophage content and CCN1 on glioma virotherapy. Mathematical Biosciences Institute, Cancer and the Immune System Workshop, Columbus, OH. November 2014.
- The role of CCN1 in glioma virotherapy with oncolytic herpes simplex virus. European Conference on Mathematical and Theoretical Biology, Gothenburg, Sweden. June 2014.
- Chronic myeloid leukemia: who can cease TKI treatment? Moffitt Cancer Center, Integrated Mathematical Oncology Personalized Medicine Workshop, Tampa, FL. November 2013.

AWARDS

Graduate Student Teaching Award University of Florida Department of Mathematics	2012
Best Poster Award African Institute for Mathematical Sciences modeling workshop	2012
Eleanor Ewing Ehrlich Award Outstanding female graduate student in mathematics	2011
Grinter Fellow University of Florida Department of Mathematics	2008
Alpha Sigma Mu National Scholar Single nationwide recipient from materials science honor society	2006

LEADERSHIP

Organizer Mathematical Biosciences Institute Professional Development Seminar	2014 - 2015
MBI Representative Field of Dreams Conference, Mesa, Arizona	2014
Treasurer and mentor University of Florida Graduate Mathematics Association	2012
President University of Florida Chapter of Alpha Sigma Mu	2006 - 2007
Co-vice president University of Florida Chapter of Habitat for Humanity	2003 - 2006

TRAINING & WORKSHOPS

Modeling the Spread and Control of Ebola in West Africa. Atlanta, GA. January 2015.

Cancer and the Immune System. Mathematical Biosciences Institute, Columbus, OH. November 2014.

Parameter Estimation for Dynamic Biological Models. National Institute for Mathematical and Biological Synthesis, Knoxville, TN. May 2014.

Integrated Mathematical Oncology Personalized Medicine. Moffitt Cancer Center, Tampa, FL. November 2013. Mathematical Methods in Systems Biology and Population Dynamics, African Institute for Mathematical Sciences, Cape Town, South Africa. January 2012.